DAN KLEIN: So before we enforce arc
consistency on a whole graph, we need
to talk about what it means for
a single arc to be consistent.
So what's an arc?
We had this constraint graph, there
weren't any arrows in it.
A constraint graph isn't
a directed thing.
You have two variables, and there's
either a constraint between them or
there isn't, right?
It's not a directional thing.
An arc is a new idea that's used
in filtering algorithms.
So it takes two variables and
it gives a direction.
So X to Y. So if we have an arc X to Y,
we're talking about variables X and
Y, and that arc is either
consistent or not.
And what it means for an arc to be
consistent is, essentially, there
aren't any constraint violations
lurking there.
What's that mean?
It means that for every value in the
tail x, there is some y in the head
which can be assigned without
violating a constraint.
Let's see an example.
So here we could look
at this constraint.
This is the constraint that
goes from the Northern
Territory to Western Australia.
And we look at this and we
check our definition.
Is there a problem here?
Is it the case that for every x in the
tail there is some y in the head that
can be assigned without violating
a constraint?
OK, well, what about for blue?
If we put blue in the tail, can
we pick something at Western
Australia and be OK?
Sure, we pick red.
We actually have no choice
at the head.
How about if we pick red
at Northern Territory?
Well, now we have a problem.
This constraint is not consistent.
I could make it consistent.
How could I make it consistent?
Red is the problem.
I could get rid of the red.
And now it would become consistent.
So it wasn't consistent before, I can
make it consistent by deleting values
from the tail.
So that I now have the property that
anything in the tail can extend
satisfactorily to the head.
How about this one?
So here we have Queensland
in the upper right,
looking at Western Australia.
Now here, every single value I can
try in the tail can extend to an
assignment to the head without
violating a constraint.
So this arc is consistent.
I don't have to do anything
to make it consistent.
So how do you remember this?
Is this directional notion?
The arc's going in the other direction
too and they may or may not be
consistent in the other direction.
An arc is a directed thing, it's
either consistent or not.
And the way you make it consistent is
you delete stuff from the tail.
How do you remember that?
Well, l like to think
about it this way.
Let's say that you're pulled over by
the constraint satisfaction police.
Well, what are they going to do?
They're going to check your trunk and
they're going to make sure there's
nothing in there that's illegal.
And so the idea with making an arc
consistent is you're going to look at
all the stuff in the trunk, that's the
tail of the arc, and if anything in
there is causing a problem, meaning if
you assigned it there would be no way
to satisfy that arc, you're going
to pull it out and delete it.
This should help you remember you always
delete from the tail of an arc.
Of course, the arc goes in the other
direction and you'll get the other
direction too at some point
in these algorithms.
All right, so what's forward checking?
What does forward checking do?
Well, if we assigned Western Australia,
we would check everything
adjacent to it.
So we check the Northern Territory
and Southern Australia.
And for each of those, we delete
anything that violates a constraint
against our assignment.
So in essence, forward checking is just
looking at the arcs that point
towards our new assignments, in this
case WA, and enforcing their
consistency.
Now, of course, forward checking
is a pretty intuitive thing.
We don't have to think
about it like this.
But it is just enforcing the consistency
of the incoming arcs.